<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on SecureBits Blog by Marcel Dellmann</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on SecureBits Blog by Marcel Dellmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 12:03:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Nmap (Network Mapper)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/nmap-network-mapper-umfassender-leitfaden/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 12:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/nmap-network-mapper-umfassender-leitfaden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


    


&lt;div class=&#34;alert danger&#34;&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;&lt;i data-feather=&#34;alert-octagon&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-most-important-thing-first&#34;&gt;The most important thing first!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the use of &lt;strong&gt;nmap&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;outside of its test/laboratory or production environment&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;may only be done with the consent of its owner&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
With this article, I hope to give you a clear understanding of the powerful tool ‘&lt;strong&gt;nmap&lt;/strong&gt;’ and also provide you with a &lt;strong&gt;PDF download of the most commonly used nmap commands&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;strong&gt;Nmap&lt;/strong&gt; is ideal for putting your IT infrastructure through its paces and is also the first vector in 99% of cases when penetration testing systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Unified Threat Management Firewall?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/what-is-a-unified-threat-management-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 05:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/what-is-a-unified-threat-management-firewall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unified-threat-management-appliances-utm-firewall&#34;&gt;Unified Threat Management Appliances (UTM Firewall)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my article “How does a firewall work?” (&lt;a href=&#34;https://secure-bits.org/wie-funktioniert-eine-firewall/%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://secure-bits.org/wie-funktioniert-eine-firewall/)&lt;/a&gt;, I described how a firewall is structured and the differences between the various types of firewalls.
In this article, I would like to give you a closer look at how a Unified Threat Management (UTM or UTM firewall) works and explain the individual functions and technical terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-difference-between-a-utm-firewall-and-a-normal-firewall&#34;&gt;What is the difference between a UTM firewall and a normal firewall?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a clear definition of this term, which specifies the designation of a security component (security appliance). For example, a pure firewall is referred to as a Specialized Security Appliance (SSA), as this network security component performs a clearly defined task in the security system. In this case, it is to prevent network connections according to a defined set of rules.
UTMA / UTM refers to security network components that combine several security components (Specialized Security Appliances (SSA)) of a network. You can find out what these are in the next paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Linux SSH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/linux/linux-ssh-absichern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/linux/linux-ssh-absichern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;securing-linux-ssh-access-correctly&#34;&gt;Securing Linux SSH access correctly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When operating a Linux server, it is usually necessary for administration purposes to establish secure access via SSH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is designed to help you successfully protect Linux SSH access against attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, securing SSH access is only one way of protecting your server against attacks. You can find more options in the tutorial “Securing Raspberry Pi from A to Z” that I published here in the blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pihole PHP 8.3 | Pihole always with the latest PHP version</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/privacy/pihole/pihole-with-the-latest-php-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/privacy/pihole/pihole-with-the-latest-php-version/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-pihole-with-php-83-on-raspberry-pi-os&#34;&gt;Installing Pihole with PHP 8.3 on Raspberry Pi OS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, ‘&lt;strong&gt;Installing Pihole with PHP 8.3&lt;/strong&gt;’, I would like to show you how to securely install a Pihole DNS server with the latest version of PHP on your Raspberry Pi in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background-to-this-tutorial&#34;&gt;Background to this tutorial&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a test installation of Pihole with Debian 11 on my Raspberry Pi, I noticed during the installation process that the installation routine on the Raspberry Pi OS lite installs PHP 7.4, which has not been provided with security updates since mid-2023 and is therefore EOL (end of life).
Further information on support for individual PHP versions can be found here:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.php.net/supported-versions.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.php.net/supported-versions.php&lt;/a&gt;
Therefore, I thought I would create a new and updated tutorial (&lt;a href=&#34;https://secure-bits.org/pi-hole-auf-einen-raspberry-pi-installieren/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;my last one was from 2022&lt;/a&gt;) so that the PHP installation used is always provided with the latest security updates.
I will also show you how to install and set up a firewall for the Raspberry Pi. And how to automatically update the system with new updates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pihole setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/privacy/pihole/pihole-basic-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/privacy/pihole/pihole-basic-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-pihole--basic-configuration&#34;&gt;Setting up Pihole – Basic configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this video tutorial, “Pi-hole Basic Configuration,” I will walk you through the setup of the Pi-hole DNS server step by step and explain what the individual functions/menu items mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IMYnydNM3rk?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions on this topic, just leave a comment either below the video on YouTube or here under this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect yourself against man-in-the-middle attacks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/man-in-the-middle-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/man-in-the-middle-secure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;protection-against-man-in-the-middle-attacks&#34;&gt;Protection against man-in-the-middle attacks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my last post - &lt;a href=&#34;https://secure-bits.org/man-in-the-middle/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Understanding Man-in-the-Middle Attacks&lt;/a&gt; - I explained what Man-in-the-Middle attacks are and what exactly they mean. In this post, I would like to give you some tips and tricks to help you protect yourself against such attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that the protective measures presented here cannot be implemented in their entirety by you, as they naturally depend on the infrastructure you use. This means, for example, whether you have your own domain or which hardware components you use in your network.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a proxy server?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/was-ist-ein-proxy-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/was-ist-ein-proxy-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;surfing-anonymously-on-the-internet&#34;&gt;Surfing anonymously on the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I will try to answer the question “What is a proxy server?” in hopefully understandable terms.
In order to surf anonymously on the Internet, the use of a proxy server is essential. In this article, you will learn what special features you need to look for when choosing a proxy server and where you can get one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A proxy server can be viewed as an intermediary or middleman in a network. It receives requests from a proxy client (e.g., desktop) and forwards them on its behalf to the target web server requested by the proxy client.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAC address – what is it?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/mac-adresse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/mac-adresse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mac-addresses&#34;&gt;MAC addresses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a &lt;strong&gt;MAC address&lt;/strong&gt; and what is it used for? In this article, I would like to explain these questions and other terms and functions related to MAC addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-mac-address&#34;&gt;What is a MAC address?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;MAC address&lt;/strong&gt; is used to identify a network-enabled device (host) in a network. This address is actually unique (more on this later) and ensures that a device can be addressed unambiguously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This address consists of a 48-bit address and should be unique worldwide. This address is assigned to layer 2 (data link layer) in the OSI model to ensure addressing in the network.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Sniffing – Secure Communication in Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/was-ist-sniffing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/was-ist-sniffing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-you-protect-yourself-against-network-sniffing&#34;&gt;How can you protect yourself against network sniffing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of you have probably read or heard somewhere that everyone is talking about secure communication. But what is secure communication and why can normal communication channels be intercepted (sniffed)? In this article, I would like to address the topic of “sniffing” and show you how you can protect yourself against such sniffing attacks.
Following Edward Snowden&amp;rsquo;s revelations, you are probably all familiar with the concept of communication channels being tapped. Tapping or sniffing can be done on both a small and large scale. Secret services use entire nodes of our ISPs (Internet Service Providers) for tapping, and on a smaller scale, this can of course also be done in your company or at home.
There are, of course, several measures that can be taken to compromise a communication channel. In this article, however, I would like to focus on what is known as “sniffing.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does a firewall work?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/wie-funktioniert-eine-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/security/wie-funktioniert-eine-firewall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-firewall-and-how-does-it-work&#34;&gt;What is a firewall and how does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I would like to answer the question “&lt;strong&gt;How does a firewall work&lt;/strong&gt;” with the help of the OSI layer model, among other things. In order to ensure security in a network, it is of course extremely important to understand how a firewall works. In this article, I will therefore attempt to explain the individual functions of a firewall in a way that is easy to understand. This will enable you to control data traffic optimally according to your requirements.
If we want to explain how a firewall works, we should first take a closer look at the OSI layer model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
